Register of the William T. Poole collection
Hoover Institution Archives
- Un-American Activities Subject File, 1920-1976 (Box 51-231.)
  - Young Socialists for Stapleton-Harris [Syd Stapleton and James Harris]. Cleveland local election campaign flyer, and Stapleton's draft notice, 1969 (Folder 229: 8)
  - Young Workers Liberation League (Folder 230)
    - Correspondence, 1970-1974. Mainly circular letters (Folder 230: 1)
    - Young Workers Liberation League issuances (Folder 230)
      - General. Leaflets, flyers, serial issues (Young Worker), and pamphlets (Liberation vs. Vietnamization; Trotskyism: The Inside), 1970-1975 (Folder 230: 2)
      - Internal documents. Convention proceedings and reports, statements, minutes, financial records, membership card, and newsletters (On the Line), 1970-1972 (Folder 230: 3)
      - Material about the Young Workers Liberation League. Clippings and HISC memoranda with accompanying documents, 1970-1973 (Folder 230: 4)
  - Youth against War and Fascism (Folder 230)
    - Correspondence, 1964-1971. Mainly circular letters (Folder 230: 5)
    - Youth against War and Fascism issuances (Folder 230)
      - General. Press releases, leaflets, flyers, newsletters, serial issues (Activist; Battle Acts; Jailbreak), and pamphlet (The Silent Slaughter: The Role of the United States in the Indonesian Massacre), 1964-1972 (Folder 230: 6)
      - Partisan. Serial issues, 1965-1970 (Folder 230: 7)
    - Material about Youth against War and Fascism. Clippings, printed article, and HUAC memoranda with exhibit issuances of Youth against War and Fascism, 1964-1968 (Folder 231: 1)
  - Youth Citizenship Fund. Leaflet and flyer, ca. 1972 (Folder 231: 2)
  - Youth International Party [Yippies]. Press releases, flyers, circulars, clippings, and radio broadcast transcript, 1968-1972 (Folder 231: 3)
  - Yugoslavia. Pamphlet (Tito's Agents in the U.S.A.), 1946 (Folder 231: 4)
  - Zinner, Arthur Hilary. Clipping, 1966 (Folder 231: 5)
  - Miscellany (Folder 231)
    - General. Letters, leaflets, flyers, circulars, serial issues, printed articles, and clippings, 1935-1974 (Folder 231: 6-7)
    - Pamphlets (The Fate of Writing in America; Hungary's Fight for Freedom; Put Yourself in Marshall's Place; Radical Periodicals in the United States, 1890-1960; Socialism in America; Trotsky: The Defeated Victor), 1945-1968 (Folder 231: 8)
- Un-American Activities Informational File, 1934-1974. (Box 232-241)
  Published and unpublished issuances of private anti-communist organizations relating to un-American activities, arranged alphabetically by name of issuing organization.
  - American Legion (Box 232)
    - General. Letters, speeches, and clipping, 1938-1966 (Folder 232: 1)
    - (Firing Line. Serial issues (Folder 232)
      - 1953-1960 (Folder 232: 2)
      - 1963-1964 (Folder 232: 3)
      - 1965-1966 (Folder 232: 4)
      - 1967-1968 (Folder 232: 5)
      - 1969-1970 (Folder 232: 6)
      - 1971-1972 (Folder 232: 7)
    - (Westchester Spotlight. Serial issues, 1966-1970 (Folder 232: 8)
  - American Mercury. Serial issues and reprint, 1956-1958 (Folder 232: 9)
  - American Security Council. Serial issues (ASC Newsletter; Nation's Security; Washington Report), 1963-1973 (Folder 232: 10)
  - Berkeley Citizens United. Serial issues (BCU Bulletin), 1971-1972 (Folder 233: 1)
  - Christian Anti-Communism Crusade. Newsletters, 1970-1971 (Folder 233: 2)
  - Christian Educational Association. Serial issues (Common Sense), 1965-1968 (Folder 233: 3)
  - Church League of America (Folder 233)
    - General. Special reports and catalog, 1969-1970 (Folder 233: 4)
    - (National Laymen's Digest. Serial issues, 1969-1972 (Folder 233: 5)
    - (News and Views. Serial issues, 1958-1974 (Folder 233: 6)
  - Citizens Anti-Communist Committee of Connecticut. Letter and flyer, 1965 (Folder 233: 7)
  - (Counterattack. Serial issues (Folder 233)
    - 1948-1955 (Folder 233: 8)
    - 1956-1959 (Folder 233: 9)
  - Daughters of the American Revolution. Speeches, 1956 (Folder 233: 10)
  - (Educational News Service. Serial issues, 1956-1957 (Folder 233: 11)
  - (Exclusive: A Digest and Analysis of Washington Intelligence for Limited Distribution. Serial issues, 1963-1970 (Folder 234: 1)
  - Fire and Police Research Association of Los Angeles. Serial issues (Bulletin; Fi-Po News; News-Notes), and pamphlet (Public Higher Education in California: Some Causes of Student Revolt), 1968-1974 (Folder 234: 2)
  - Freedom Forum. Pamphlets (The Communist Conspiracy; Dangers to U.S. Internal Security), 1951-1959 (Folder 234: 3)
  - Hawaii Foundation for American Freedoms. Serial issues (Criterion; Fact Finder; Spotlight), 1960-1971 (Folder 234: 4)
  - (Herald of Freedom. Serial issues, 1962-1966 (Folder 234: 5)
  - Hoover Institution on War, Revolution and Peace (Folder 234)
    - (New Left Monthly Report. Serial issues (Folder 234)
      - 1970 (Folder 234: 6)
      - 1971 (Folder 234: 7-8)
      - 1972 (Folder 235: 1-2)
    - Booklet (Territorial Claims in the Sino-Soviet Conflict), 1965 (Folder 235: 3)
  - (Human Events. Serial issues, 1967-1972 (Folder 235: 4)
  - (Internal Security Report: A Counter-Subversive and Intelligence Publication. Serial issue, 1969 (Folder 235: 5)
  - John Birch Society. Reprints from (American Opinion, 1967-1971 (Folder 235: 6)
  - Legion for Truth. Circulars, 1968 (Folder 235: 7)
  - (National Republic: A Magazine of Fundamental Americanism (Folder 235)
    - Serial issues (Folder 235)
      - 1934 (Folder 235: 8)
      - 1938 (Folder 235: 9)
      - 1939 (Folder 235: 10)
      - 1940 (Folder 236: 1)
      - 1941 (Folder 236: 2)
      - 1942 (Folder 236: 3)
      - 1943 (Folder 236: 4)
      - 1944 (Folder 236: 5)
      - 1946 (Folder 236: 6)
      - 1947 (Folder 236: 7)
      - 1948 (Folder 236: 8)
      - 1949 (Folder 236: 9)
      - 1950 (Folder 236: 10)
      - 1951 (Folder 236: 11)
      - 1952 (Folder 236: 12)
      - 1953 (Folder 236: 13)
      - 1954 (Folder 236: 14)
      - 1955 (Folder 237: 1)
      - 1956 (Folder 237: 2)
      - 1957 (Folder 237: 3)
      - 1958 (Folder 237: 4)
      - 1959 (Folder 237: 5)
      - 1960 (Folder 237: 6)
    - Miscellany. Article reprints and Lettergrams, 1935-ca. 1950s (Folder 237: 7)
  - Newsletter Company. Newsletters, 1947 (Folder 237: 8)
  - Osth Information Service (Folder 238)
    - Newsletters (Folder 238)
      - 1968-1970 (Folder 238: 1)
      - 1971-1973 (Folder 238: 2)
    - Miscellany. Letter and catalog, 1970-1972 (Folder 238: 3)
  - Racht, Leon, and Jack Lotto. Scrapbook of newspaper column clippings, including "The Red Letter" by Leon Racht, ca. 1950s, and "On Your Guard" by Jack Lotto, 1959-1960 (Folder 238: 4)
  - (Tactics. Serial issues, 1967 (Folder 238: 5)
  - (Tocsin. Serial issues, 1961-1966 (Folder 238: 6)
  - U.S. Anti-Communist Congress. Newsletters (Washington Intelligence Report), 1968-1971 (Folder 239: 1)
  - Young Americans for Freedom. Satirical fake issues of Communist Party publications, with letter and other enclosures, 1966-1971 (Folder 239: 2)
  - Miscellany. Letters, leaflets, flyers, circulars, serial issues, and printed articles, 1938-1972 (Folder 239: 3)
- United States Government Agencies File, 1934-1976. (Box 239-241)
  Published and unpublished issuances of United States government agencies relating to un-American activities, and published and unpublished issuances of private sources relating to those government agencies, arranged alphabetically by name of United States government agency
  - Civil Service Commission. Memoranda enumerating organizations on Attorney General's subversive list, and modifications thereto, 1950-1952 (Folder 239: 4)
  - Department of Justice. Press releases, statements, subversive organizations list, and petition against the Department's use of paid informers, 1953-1971 (Folder 239: 5)
  - Department of the Army. Security education booklet, 1972 (Folder 239: 6)
  - Federal Bureau of Investigation. Press releases, excerpts from annual reports, "The Extremist Speaks" issuances of the Bureau, and J. Edgar Hoover interview transcript, 1951-1971 (Folder 239: 7)
  - House Un-American Activities Committee/House Internal Security Committee (Folder 239)
    - Correspondence, 1951-1973. (Folder 239: 8)
      Includes circular letters. Includes both letters supporting and letters opposing HUAC/HISC
    - HUAC/HISC issuances (Folder 239)
      - Public issuances (Miscellaneous). Congressional speeches and printed report (The Communist-Led Riots against the House Committee on Un-American Activities in San Francisco, Calif., May 12-14, 1960), 1946-1973 (Folder 239: 9)
      - Internal documents (Miscellaneous). Notes, memoranda, and draft fragments, 1942-1967 (Folder 240: 1)
      - Index of hearings of predecessor Special Committee on Un-American Activities (John W. McCormack Committee), 1934 (Folder 240: 2)
      - List of hearing exhibits, ca. 1940 (Folder 240: 3)
      - Proposed amendments to Internal Security Act. Bills, press release, and memoranda, 1965-1967 (Folder 240: 4)
      - Finances. Memoranda and printed Congressional budget data, 1968-1975 (Folder 240: 5)
    - Material about HUAC/HISC. Includes both material supporting and material opposing HUAC/HISC (Folder 240)
      - General. Clippings, printed articles, leaflets, flyers, and circulars, 1943-1975 (Folder 240: 6)
      - Statements and press releases, 1948-1971. (Folder 240: 7)
        Includes House Democratic Party Study Group resolution re abolition
      - Petitions for abolition of HUAC/HISC, and legal motions in case regarding HUAC (Krebs et al. vs. Ashbrook et al.) before U.S. District Court for the District of Columbia, 1943-1972 (Folder 240: 8)
      - Pamphlets (Dialogue on the Constitutionality of the Committee on Un-American Activities of the House of Representatives; House Un-American Activities Committee: Bulwark of Segregation; Operation Abolition: Some Facts and Some Comments; A Quarter-Century of Un-Americana: A Tragico-Comical Memorabilia of HUAC), 1961-1965 (Folder 241: 1)
  - Postal Inspection Service. Bulletin, law enforcement report, and pamphlet ((Mail Fraud Laws), 1970-1976 (Folder 241: 2)
  - Senate Internal Security Committee. Flyer and clippings, 1953-1975 (Folder 241: 3)
  - Subversive Activities Control Board (Folder 241)
    - Subversive Activities Control Board statements, 1970-1972. (Folder 241: 4)
      Includes lists of defunct organizations on Attorney General's subversive list
    - Material about the Subversive Activities Control Board (Folder 241)
      - General. Clippings, printed articles, and petitions for abolition of the Board and repeal of the Internal Security Act, 1952-1967. (Folder 241: 5)
        Includes complaint in the case of American Servicemen's Union et al. vs. Mitchell et al. before U.S. District Court for the District of Columbia
      - Congressional documents. Budget data re Board, and HISC printed report (Additional Function for Subversive Activities Control Board), 1972 (Folder 241: 6)
  - Supreme Court. Library of Congress Legislative Reference Service study "Cases Relating to Communist and Subversive Activities Appealed to the Supreme Court of the United States,", 1968 (Folder 241: 7)
- Audiovisual File, 1946-1971. (Box 242)
  Photographs relating to Subversive Activities Control Board or un-American activities investigations
  - Subversive Activities Control Board Docket 104-53: National Council of American-Soviet Friendship. Photograph of John Alfred Rossen, 1948 (Folder 242: 1)
  - Subversive Activities Control Board Docket 108-53: Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade. Photographs mainly of Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade contingents in parades, 1946-1952 (Folder 242: 2)
  - Subversive Activities Control Board Docket 111-53: United May Day Committee. Photographs of May Day parades, 1948-1955 (Folder 242: 3-4)
  - Antiwar demonstrations. Photographs of antiwar demonstrations, 1970-1971 (Folder 242: 5)
  - Eisler, Hanns. Portraits of Hanns Eisler, undated (Folder 242: 6)
  - Lenin, V. I. Portrait of V. I. Lenin, undated (Folder 242: 7)
  - Reed, Dean. Hollywood publicity photograph of Dean Reed, 1971 (Folder 242: 8)
  - Socialist Workers Party. Photograph of Boston mayoral candidates, including Socialist Workers Party candidate John E. Powers, 1971 (Folder 242: 9)
  - Spring Mobilization Committee. Photographs of New York City antiwar demonstration organized by Spring Mobilization Committee, 1967 (Folder 242: 10)
  - Vietnam War. Photographs of Vietnam War scenes distributed by North Vietnamese government and/or South Vietnamese National Liberation Front, 1971 (Folder 242: 11)
  - Workers League. Photograph of Workers League contingent in parade, undated (Folder 242: 12)